Guide to the Cleveland Robinson Papers WAG.006.001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Cleveland Robinson Papers
1956-1992
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Robinson, Cleveland L. (Cleveland Lowellyn), 1914-1995
Distributive, Processing, and Office Workers of America. District 65
WAG.006.001
17 Linear Feet (17 boxes)
Cleveland Robinson (1914-1995) was an African American trade union leader and civil rights activist who served as Secretary-Treasurer of the United Auto Workers of America, District 65, from 1952-1992. The collection contains correspondence, miscellaneous documents, ephemera and clippings.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by the United Automobile, Aircraft, and Vehicle Workers of America. District 65, in 1992, at the time of Cleveland Robinson's retirement and the dissolution of District 65 into ten separate locals within the UAW. The accession number associated with this gift is 1992.005.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
Cleveland Robinson was born in 1914 in Swabys Hope, a rural parish of Jamaica. After serving as a local constable and an elementary school teacher, he emigrated to the United States in 1944. On arrival he took a job in a Manhattan dry goods store and very soon became active in District 65, Distributive Workers. After organizing his own shop in 1947, he went on to become a steward, and then a full-time organizer for the union. He was elected vice-president in 1950 and secretary-treasurer in 1952, a position he held until his retirement in 1992. During the period when District 65 was affiliated with the Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Workers Union (RWDSU), Robinson held the positions of international vice-president and executive board member of that union. After longstanding disagreements with the RWDSU about the pace of organizing in the South and efforts to reach minority workers, District 65 pulled out and organized the National Council of Distributive Workers of America; Cleveland Robinson was elected president of the new body. District 65 finally affiliated with the United Auto Workers (UAW) in 1981. At that time the union was comprised of 33,000 members, one half of whom were women, and one third minority workers; it had locals in 37 states, Canada and Puerto Rico.
A close associate of A. Philip Randolph, Robinson was founding member and vice-president of the Negro American Labor Council; he assumed the presidency of the 40,000-member NALC when Randolph retired in 1966. In 1971 he helped to found the Council of Black Trade Unionists, successor organization to the NALC, and served as its first vice president.
In addition to his union activity, Cleveland Robinson was a stalwart of the civil rights movement. He was administrative chairman and one of the key organizers of the August 1963 March on Washington for Jobs and Freedom. A friend and advisor on labor matters to Martin Luther King, Jr., he was an active member of the National Urban League and the NAACP, a director of the Southern Christian leadership Council, and a trustee of the Martin Luther King, Jr. Center in Atlanta, GA. He was also a leader in the struggle to mobilize American opposition to apartheid in South Africa and supported movements for labor and human rights in many African nations. He sat on the steering committee of the American Committee for Africa, and served as Commissioner of the New York City Commission for Human Rights during the administrations of Mayors Wagner and Lindsay. As co-chair of the committee that organized Nelson Mandela's visit to New York City in 1990, he spearheaded a massive fund-raising campaign among the city's trade unions to defray the expenses of the event. At the time of his death he was chair of the New York State Martin Luther King, Jr., Commission, which worked toward having King's birthday declared a legal holiday and sponsors observances of the day and educational programs focusing on civil rights throughout the state each year. He was the recipient of New York State's Martin Luther King, Jr. Medal of Freedom in 1987 and the Eugene V. Debs/Norman Thomas Award of the New York Democratic Socialists of America in 1984.
His first wife was Sue Eliza Robinson, a department store worker and member of District 65; and they had two sons and a daughter. After her death in 1976 he married again, Doreen McPherson Robinson. He suffered severely from glaucoma for many years, and was considered legally blind by 1970; but his level of commitment and activity was in no way impaired by this disability. He never lost touch with his Jamaican origins and traveled to the island often, keeping up a keen interest in a number of Jamaican-American political, cultural and fraternal organizations. Cleveland Robinson died of kidney failure in New York City in August 1995.
Scope and Content Note
Series 1. UAW, District 65 Files, 1956-1992, includes a wide range of documentation of every aspect of union affairs: organizing files, grievances, bargaining records, financial reports, benefits files, legal records, and officers' and members' correspondence. Also documented are the union's extensive educational and cultural programs, and its special interest in organizing in the South. Series 2. General and Political Files, 1960-1992, provides a detailed picture of Robinson's political interests and affiliations. Included are records of his involvement in African affairs, anti-apartheid campaigns, the Coalition of Black Trade Unionists, the King Center in Atlanta, New York City and state human rights and civil rights commissions, and a wide range of smaller campaigns and organizations. Also included is his correspondence with leading political and cultural figures, trade unionists, and personal friends, as well as letters from ordinary workers, both in the U.S. and in Jamaica.
Arrangement
The folders in each series are arranged alphabetically.
Organized into two series:
Missing Title
1. UAW, District 65 Files, 1956-1992
2. General and Political Files, 1960-1992
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
United Automobile Workers of America, District 65 Records (WAG 006)
United Automobile Workers of America Oral Histories (OH 019)
United Automobile Workers of America Photographs (PHOTOS 023)
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu, (212) 998-2630 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
African American labor leaders.; Civil rights -- United States.; Correspondence.; Anti-communist movements -- United States.; American Committee for Africa; International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace, and Agricultural Implement Workers of America. District 65; New York State Martin Luther King, Jr. Commission; Coalition of Black Trade Unionists (U.S.); New York (N.Y.). City Commission on Human Rights; King, Martin Luther, Jr., 1929-1968; Martin Luther King, Jr. Center for Nonviolent Social Change; Distributive, Processing, and Office Workers of America. District 65
- Series I: UAW, District 65 Files, 1956-1992.
  - Atlanta, GA: Robinson Correspondence File, 1970-1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bargaining, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bell Fibre Products (Columbus, GA), 1985-1992 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bell, James: Death, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Black Affairs Committee of District 65, 1988, 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Boston Office, District 65, 1986-1991 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Building (13 Astor Place), 1980, 1987, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Campbell's Soup Company, 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Cargill, Inc., 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Champion Packages (Columbus, GA), 1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Check-Off: Delinquent, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Constitution (District 65), 1974 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Contracts: New Expirations, etc., 1990 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Contributions, 1974-1979 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Distributive Workers of America: National Council, 1969-1973 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Distributive Workers of America, 1970, 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Distributive Workers of America: Report by Cleveland Robinson, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - District 19 (Memphis, TN), 1981 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - District 19 (Memphis, TN), 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence (UAW, District 65), undated, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence: Members, 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence: Members, 1971-1974 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence: Members, 1976-1981 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence: Members, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence: Members, 1987-1992 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence: Unions, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence: Unions, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence: Unions, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Crawford, Elisabeth v. Distributive Workers of America, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Dailey, Thelma v. UAW, District 65, 1978-1981 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Development & Training Center, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Detroit: Council 30, 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - District 65: General, 1979-1992 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - District 65: History, 1969, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - District 65: Minutes; General Council, 1982-1990 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Division 19: Vintage Mobile Homes, Inc., 1977-1981 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Division 19: Memphis, TN, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Division 19: District 65; Memphis TN, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Division 19: Memphis TN, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Division 19: Memphis TN, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Division 19: Memphis TN, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Division 19: Memphis TN, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Donations, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Drexel Chemical Corp., 1984 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Education Fund, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Education Fund, 1978-1981 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Education Fund, 1982-1987 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Education Fund, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Education Fund, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Education Fund, 1990-1992 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Education Fund: Job Skills Program, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Education Opportunities, 1982, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Education Programs, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Eisner and Levy, Planning Council, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Eisner and Levy, Planning Council, 1983-1985 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Eisner, Levy, Pollar and Ratner, 1991-1993 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Elder Mayflower (Jacksonville, FL), 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Employment Office: Hiring Hall, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Enforcement of Union Rules, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Farm-workers, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - "Fight Back" Fund, 1983, 1990-1992 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Finances, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Finances, 1989-1992 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Finances: Contributions, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Financial Reports, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Financial Statements, 1973-1975 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Fisk University (Local 19 A), 1977-1979 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Fisk University (Local 19 A), 1980-1982 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Fisk University (Local 19 A), 1983-1989 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Fisk University (Local 19 A), 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Florida Feed Mills, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - General Office Executive Board, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Gibraltar Rehabilitation Company, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 17A)
  - Glemby Company, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Glemby Company, 1983-1986 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Glemby Company, 1987-1990 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Gordon, Michael S. (Attorney), 1985-1991 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Gordon, Michael S., 1992 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Grody, Donald, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Hiring Hall (District 65), 1970 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Hofstra College Program, 1971, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - IRS Statement, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Interoffice Memos, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Interoffice Memos, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Interoffice Memos, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Interoffice Memos, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Johnson, Jimmy, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 1a)
  - King Commemorative Meeting (District 65), 1978 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - King, Dr. Martin Luther, JR: District 65, undated, 1956-1969 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - King, Dr. Martin Luther, JR: District 65 Rally, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - King-Osman Fund, 1987-1990 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - King-Osman Fund, 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Labor-University Alliance, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - La Salle Strike: Scabs, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Laundry Workers: FL & GA, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Legal Aid, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Legal Aid Strike, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Legal Aid Strike, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Legal Matters (District 65), 1998-1986 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Legislative, 1990-1992 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Lerner Company, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Local 19 (Memphis TN), 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Local 19 (Memphis TN), 1980-1982 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Local 19 (Memphis TN), 1987-1989 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Local 19 (Memphis TN), 1992 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Local 19, 19A (Memphis TN), 1973-1981 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Local 26 (Suffolk, VA), 1960-1969 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Local 26 (Suffolk, VA), 1970-1978 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Local 26 (Suffolk, VA), 1980-1986 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Local 26 (Suffolk, VA), 1988-1990, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Local 28 (Charleston, VA), 1971-1980 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Local 28 (Charleston, NC), 1987-1989 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Local 28 (Charleston, NC), 1991 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Local 67 (Muscogee Lumber Company), 1969-1974 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Local 67 (Columbus, OH), 1971-1974 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Local 67 (Columbus, OH), 1975-1981 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Local 589 (Jacksonville, FL), 1976-1981 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Local 885 (Miami, FL), 1975-1987 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Long Island Executive Board: Minutes, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Memos (District 65), 1968-1981, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Memos (District 65), 1988 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Memos (District 65), 1989-1991 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Mississippi: Cotton Choppers Strike, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - National Council of Distributive Workers of America: Formation, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - National Labor Relations Board: Cases, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - New Jersey Convention Report, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - New Jersey Division, 1982, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - New Jersey Office, 1987-1989 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - New Members Booklet, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - New York City Central Labor Council, 1985-1987 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - New York City Central Labor Council, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 17A)
  - New York City Central Labor Council, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - New York City Central Labor Council, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - New York City Central Labor Council, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Oath of Office/ Installation Ceremony, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 20A)
  - Old Dutch Mustard Company, Inc., 1983-1985 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Out-of-Town Shops, 1973-1975 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Pillowtex Corporation, 1985-1988 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Pillowtex Corporation, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Restructuring, Sub-Committee on, undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Retirees List, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Rules and Regulations: Enforcement, 1982-1984 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Security Plan, 1970-1978 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Security Plan, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Security Plan, 1981-1983 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Security Plan, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Security Plan, 1984-1986 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Security Plan, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Security Plan, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Security Plan, 1988-1989 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Security Plan, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Security Plan, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Security Plan, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Security Plan: Correspondence, 1977-1980 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Security Plan: Delinquents, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Security Plan: Michael Gordon Opinion, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Security Plan: Monitor, M. Lynch, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Security Plan: M. Segal Co., 1992 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Security Plan: Trustees, 1982-1984 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Security Plan: Trustees, 1985-1987 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Security Plan: Trustees, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Security Plan: Trustees, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Stewards, 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Stewards Attendance, 1979-1980 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Tax Returns, 1982-1985 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Training Fund, 1979-1980 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - United Auto Workers: Conferences, 1991-1992 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - UAW: General, 1980-1986 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - UAW: General, 1987-1990 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - UAW: General, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - UAW: General, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - UAW: Region 8, 1981-1984 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - UAW: Region 8, 1987-1988 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - UAW: Region 9A, 1982-1984 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - UAW: District 9A, 1987-1989 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Workplace Literary Project, 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Series II: General and Political Files, 1960-1992.
  - Abu-Jamal, Mumia, 1989-1991 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Affirmative Action (Federal Contracts), 1981 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Africa: General, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Africa: General, 1985-1987 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Africa: General, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Africa: General, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Africa: General, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Africa: General, 1991-1992 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - African National Congress (ANC), 1990 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - ANC, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - ANC, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - American Committee on Africa, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - American Committee on Africa, 1985-1986 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Americans for Democratic Action, 1963-1964, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Anti-Apartheid, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Anti-Apartheid, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Anti-Apartheid, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Anti-Apartheid, 1986-1988 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Anti-Apartheid, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Anti-Apartheid (UAW), 1986-1988 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Antigua, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Appeal for Human Dignity Now, 1961-1967, undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Association of Legal Aid Attorneys, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Black Issues: General, 1983-1984, 1988-1992 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Boy Scouts of America: NYC Labor Luncheon, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Branch, Taylor, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Building Trades: Discrimination, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Central America/ South America, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Chaney, Goodman & Schwerner Memorial, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - City Hall, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - City Sun, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Clippings, Misc., 1960, 1985-1986 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Coalition of Black Trade Unionists, 1971-1973 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Coalition of Black Trade Unionists, 1974-1975 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Coalition of Black Trade Unionists, 1976-1978 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Coalition of Black Trade Unionists, 1979-1980 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Coalition of Black Trade Unionists, 1982-1983 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Coalition of Black Trade Unionists, 1984-1985 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Coalition of Black Trade Unionists, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Coalition of Black Trade Unionists, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Coalition of Black Trade Unionists, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Coalition of Black Trade Unionists, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Coalition of Black Trade Unionists, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Coalition of Black Trade Unionists, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Coalition of Black Trade Unionists, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Coalition of Black Trade Unionists, 1992-1993 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Coalition of Black Trade Unionists: Chicago Conference, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Coalition of Black Trade Unionists: Convention, 1973-1974 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Coalition of Black Trade Unionists: Convention, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Coalition of Black Trade Unionists: Conventions, 1978-1979, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Coalition of Black Trade Unionists: Convention, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Coalition of Black Trade Unionists: Executive Committee, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Coalition of Black Trade Unionists: Executive Council, 1973-1990 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Coalition of Black Trade Unionists: New York Chapter, 1973, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Committee on Education and Labor (US Congress): Testimony, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Congress on Racial Equality, 1960-1968 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Congressional Black Caucus Foundation, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: General, 1959-1966 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: General, 1967-1972 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: General, 1973-1980 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: General, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: General, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: General, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: General, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: General, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: General, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: General (I), 1987 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: General (II), 1987 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: General (I), 1988 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: General (II), 1988 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: General, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: General, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: General, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: General, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: General, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Curtis (Mark) Defense, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Davis, Ossie, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Democratic Party: National Convention, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Democratic Socialists of America, 1987, 1990-1991 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Dinkins, David, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Dubois, W. E. B., Memorial Program, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Education: African American Children, 1990-1991 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Freedom National Bank, 1965-1969 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Friends of Norman Thomas Committee, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Full Employment Action Council, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Gandhi Society of Human Rights, 1962-1966 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Guatemala, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Haiti, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Harlem Parents Committee, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Haryou-Azt, 1963-1967 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Hizz, Herbert, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Humphrey-Hawkins, Bill, 1976-1980 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Interracial Council for Business Opportunity, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Israel-South Africa Relations, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Jackson, Joseph T., 1980 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Jamaica, 1966-1979 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Jamaica, 1984-1990 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Jamaica: Flood Relief, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Jamaica: Progressive League, 1974-1979 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Jamaica: Support Committee, 1980, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B., 1962-1963 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Jones, Thomas R., 1963-1968 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - June 12th Rally (Disarmament), 1982 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Kennedy, Robert F., 1967 (Box 12, Folder 30A)
  - King Center, 1969-1973 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - King Center, 1974-1976 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - King Center, 1977-1979 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - King Center, 1980-1981 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - King Center, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - King Center, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - King Center, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - King Center, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - King Center, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 3)